<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="https://tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="https://cwrc.ca/templates/css/tei.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
	<teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
				<title>Are Women People?</title>
				<author>Alice Duer Miller</author>
				<editor>Amelia Flynn</editor>
				<respStmt>
					<resp>TEI Encoding</resp>
					<name>Amelia Flynn</name>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>CTS*4020: Digital Research Project</publisher>
				<address>
					<orgName>University of Guelph</orgName>
					<settlement>Guelph</settlement>
					<postCode>N1G 2W1</postCode>
					<country>Canada</country>
				</address>
				<date when="2025">2025</date>
				<distributor>University of Guelph</distributor>
				<authority>Amelia Flynn</authority>
			</publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Are Women People?</title>
          <title>New York Tribune</title>
          <note>Column</note>
          <date>1914-04-19</date>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
		<xenoData><rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:as="http://www.w3.org/ns/activitystreams#" xmlns:cwrc="http://sparql.cwrc.ca/ontologies/cwrc#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:geo="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#" xmlns:oa="http://www.w3.org/ns/oa#" xmlns:schema="http://schema.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#" xmlns:fabio="https://purl.org/spar/fabio#" xmlns:bf="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/bif#" xmlns:cito="https://sparontologies.github.io/cito/current/cito.html#" xmlns:org="http://www.w3.org/ns/org#"/></xenoData></teiHeader>
  <text>
    <front>
      <div type="header">
        <dateline>19 April, 1914</dateline>
        <head type="main">ARE WOMEN PEOPLE?</head>
        <head type="sub">By Alice Duer Miller</head>
      </div>
    </front>

    <body>
      <div type="column">
        <div type="section" n="1">
        	<head>UNION LEAGUE CLUB REPORTED IN FAVOR OF SUFFRAGE.</head>
        	<p>The <orgName>Union League Club</orgName>, having, as it says of itself, invariably given its support to measures extending and securing human rights, reported that "on the question of equal suffrage . . . our principles are not unknown;. . . they are comprised in two words—justice and security."
        	</p>
        	<p>But that was in 1868, when they were all a good deal younger, and when they were speaking of negroes—not of the women of <placeName>New York State</placeName>.
        	</p>
        </div>
      	<div type="section" n="2">
      		<head>SAFETY FIRST.
      		</head>
      		<p>The <orgName>Royal Commission (English) on Civil Service</orgName>—a majority of which are men—has just issued a report stating, among other things, that, so far as the efficiency of men is higher than that of women, men's salaries should continue to be higher.
      		</p>
      		<p>And then, lest they should ever be proved wrong, they recommend that the highest examinations should not be open to women.
      		</p>
      	</div>
      	<div type="section" n="3">
      		<head>IN WHOSE HOME?
      		</head>
      		<p>"No," said he, "for you see I believe that woman's place is the home."
      		</p>
      		<p>Investigation showed that in order to run his home, educate his children and manage his office he was keeping thirteen women out of their homes and only one in it.
      		</p>
      	</div>
      	<div type="section" n="4">
      		<head>PLEASE LET HER, GENTLEMEN.
      		</head>
      		<p>"I am convinced," <persName>Dr. Lyman Abbott</persName> is reported to have said, "that in spite of all this talk of sex equality woman in her heart still longs to look up to man with reverence.”
      		</p>
      		
      	</div>
      	<div type="section" n="5">
      		<head>AN EXPLANATION—NOT AN EXCUSE.
      		</head>
      		<p>Testifying before the Committee on Ventilation in the House of Parliament, <persName>Sir R. Pole-Carew</persName> said that the air of the House "caused sleepiness and confusion of the brain."
      		</p>
      		
      	</div>
      	<div type="section" n="6">
      		<head>SEX LIMITATIONS.
      		</head>
      		<p>Speaking of the Ulster volunteer force, <title>"The Westminster Gazette"</title> says: "The ladies with the Red Cross bandages made a better and more soldier-like appearance when they, assembled and marched through the streets than did the men."
      		</p>
      		<p>But, as R. W. D. points out, men have turned out to be better cooks and dressmakers than women, so no one need feel hurt.
      		</p>
      	</div>
      	<div type="section" n="7">
      		<head>ASSETS—AND LIABILITIES?
      		</head>
      		<p>State Senator William H. Berry, of Pennsylvania, says that the assets of this country are not in dollars and cents, or battleships, or mines, or canals, but in the manhood of the nation. This statement was warmly applauded by many hundreds of men.
      		</p>
      		
      	</div>
      	<div type="section" n="8">
      		<head>SOME PEOPLE'S IDEA OF EQUALITY.
      		</head>
      		<p>Women have been admitted to active membership in the Automobile Club of America.
      		</p>
      		<p>"This is the first time in the history of motoring," says "The New York Times," "that women have received the same privileges as the male members. Membership carries all the regular privileges of the members except the power to vote and an equity in the club property."
      		</p>
      	</div>
      	<div type="section" n="9">
      		<head>THE PROTECTED SEX.
      		</head>
      		<p>In 1770 the following act was passed in England:
      		</p>
      		<p>"That all women of whatever age, rank, profession or degree, whether virgins, maids or widows, that shall from and after such act impose upon, seduce or betray into matrimony any of his majesty's male subjects by the scents, paints, cosmetic washes, artificial teeth, false hair. Spanish wool, iron stays, hoops, high heeled shoes, etc., shall incur the penalty of the law now in force against witchcraft and like misdemeanors, and that the marriage upon conviction shall stand null and void."
      		</p>
      	</div>
      	<div type="section" n="10">
      		<head>IN ORDER OF MERIT.
      		</head>
      		<p>Four more dogs have been added to the New York police force. The intimation is that when every station house has been equipped with a good mouser the de- partment will take up the question of policewomen.
      		</p>
      		
      	</div>
      	<div type="section" n="11">
      		<head>MUTUAL VOWS.
      		</head>
      		<lg><l>"My dear," he said, "observe this frightful bill,</l>
      		<l>Run up, I think you'll own, against my will</l>
      		<l>If you will recollect our wedding day,</l>
      		<l>You vowed on that occasion 'to obey.’“</l>
      		<l>"I do recall the day," said she, "and how</l>
      		<l>Me with your worldly goods you did endow."</l>
      		<l>"That," he replied, "is palpably absurd"—</l>
      		<l>"You mean you did not mean to keep your word?"</l>
      		<l>"Oh, yes," he answered, "in a general way."</l>
      		<l>"And that," she said, "is how I meant 'obey.’"</l></lg>
      		
      	</div>
      	<div type="section" n="12">
      		<head>WE KNOW OF NO AGE WHEN THEY WERE SO CONSIDERED.
      		</head>
      		<p>The question, "Are Women People?" is being a good deal discussed by men's debating clubs this season.
      		</p>
      	</div>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>