<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="https://tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="https://cwrc.ca/templates/css/tei.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
	<teiHeader>
		 <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
				<title>Are Women People?</title>
				<author>Alice Duer Miller</author>
				<editor>Amelia Flynn</editor>
				<respStmt>
					<resp>TEI Encoding</resp>
					<name>Amelia Flynn</name>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>CTS*4020: Digital Research Project</publisher>
				<address>
					<orgName>University of Guelph</orgName>
					<settlement>Guelph</settlement>
					<postCode>N1G 2W1</postCode>
					<country>Canada</country>
				</address>
				<date when="2025">2025</date>
				<distributor>University of Guelph</distributor>
				<authority>Amelia Flynn</authority>
			</publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Are Women People?</title>
          <title>New York Tribune</title>
          <note>Column</note>
          <date/>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
		<xenoData><rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:as="http://www.w3.org/ns/activitystreams#" xmlns:cwrc="http://sparql.cwrc.ca/ontologies/cwrc#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:geo="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#" xmlns:oa="http://www.w3.org/ns/oa#" xmlns:schema="http://schema.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#" xmlns:fabio="https://purl.org/spar/fabio#" xmlns:bf="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/bif#" xmlns:cito="https://sparontologies.github.io/cito/current/cito.html#" xmlns:org="http://www.w3.org/ns/org#"/></xenoData></teiHeader>
<text>
    <front>
      <div type="header">
		<dateline>March 15, 1914</dateline>
        <head type="main">ARE WOMEN PEOPLE?</head>
        <head type="sub">By Alice Duer Miller</head>
      </div>
    </front>

    <body>
      <div type="article">
        <div type="section" n="">
          <head>Pansies, Perhaps—That's for Thoughts.</head>
          <p>"On the morning when it (the municipal woman suffrage bill in Kansas in 1887) was considered, a large and beautiful bouquet of flowers was placed on the desk of <persName>Senator Pickler</persName>. On a card attached was written: 'From the women of Kansas who do not wish to vote. History honors the man who dares do right.’ When the discussion was over it was finally discovered that no woman had anything to do with sending the flowers, but that they had been purchased and presented by the liquor interests, who have always opposed woman's suffrage."— Speech of <persName>Senator Thompson</persName>, of Kansas, in the Senate, March 4.</p>
        </div>
        <div type="section" n="">
          <head>Final Words.</head>
          <p>"I," said <persName>Senator Williams</persName>, of Mississippi, "shall say nothing about the 'superiority' of man to woman; or the 'superiority' of woman to man. Man being superior to woman in some respects, and woman superior to man in other respects, and (he startled his audience by adding) each being inferior to the other in certain respects."</p>
        </div>
        <div type="section" n="">
          <head>Did You Know</head>
          <p>That the wife of <persName>Senator Martine</persName>, of New Jersey, does not want to vote?</p>
		  <p>That the mother of Senator Martine, of New Jersey, did not want to vote, and that he thanks God for it?</p>
		  <p>That he prefers a low, tender tone to the high shrieking voice of woman dragging her sister to the ballot box?</p>
		  <p>That <persName>Senator Shafroth</persName> has lived in Denver thirty-four years and has never heard women shrieking at the ballot box?</p>
		  <p>That <persName>Senator Chamberlain</persName> has four daughters, and that they come home from the polls, in his opinion, as pure and refined as they went?</p>
		  <p>That <persName>Senator Bryan</persName>, of Florida, would not like to see a woman in the Cabinet, and that Senator Thomas feels sure he will see it, if he lives his allotted time.</p>
		  <p>That <persName>Senator Williams</persName>, of Mississippi, thinks it would take more than the ballot to degrade the sweet womanhood of his state?</p>
        </div>
        <div type="section" n="">
          <head/>
          <lg>
			<l>Sylvia, my dear, I would be yours with pleasure,</l>        		
        		<l>All that you are seems excellent to me,</l>
        		<l>Except your mother, who's much more at leisure</l>
        		<l>Than mothers ought to be.</l>
        		<l>Find her a fad, a job, an occupation,</l>
        		<l>Eugenics, dancing, uplift, yes, or crime,</l>
        		<l>Set her to work at her Emancipation,—</l>
        		<l>That takes a lot of time.</l>
        		<l>Or if the suffrage doctrine fails to charm her,</l>
        		<l>There are the Antis—rather in her line—</l>
        		<l>Guarding the Home, from Maine to Alabama</l>
        		<l>Would keep her out of mine.</l>
        		<l>W. G.</l>
		  </lg>
        </div>
        <div type="section" n="">
          <head>No Place for Ladies!</head>
          <p>A bill is now before the Assembly Judiciary Committee calling for two women referees in the New York Children's courts, where the cases of over 2,000 girls are passed on yearly.</p>
		  <p>In case the gentlemen of the committee incline to the belief that the only children a woman ought to be interested in are her own children, we call their attention to this:</p>
		  		  <p>"In a recent trial for rape in Chicago, counsel for the defence asked to have the two women present—a truant officer and an agent for the Vice Commission—leave the courtroom. The judge allowed them to remain. To one of them the little girl, who occupied the witness chair for a day and a half, said later: 'The men looked at each other, and smiled at what I said; that was what made me get so nervous and jerk so.'"—<persName>E. C. Parsons</persName>: "The Old Fashioned Woman."</p>

        </div>
        <div type="section" n="">
          <head>The Good Old Days.</head>
          <p>"The Roman husbands did not divorce their wives. They killed them." —Quoted in "Woman," by <persName>J. Donaldson</persName></p>
        </div>
        <div type="section" n="">
          <head>Coming and Going.</head>
          <p>A painstaking article in "The Pall Mall Gazette" designed to throw light on the equal pay for equal work situation seems to come impartially to the following conclusions:</p>

		  <p>(a) That if women's wages are as high as men's women will have no temptations to marry.</p>
		  <p>(b) That if women's wages are as high as men's, the positions will always go to men, and no occupation will be open to women, except matrimony.</p>
        </div>
        <div type="section" n="">
          <head>But Who Cares for Figures?</head>
          <p>One of the arguments against paying women as highly as men for the same work is that women are only temporarily in industry, while men are permanent.</p>
		  <p>Forty-four per cent. of the women teachers in the New York public schools have been more than ten years in the service, whereas only 26 per cent. of the men teachers have served as long.</p>
        </div>
        <div type="section" n="">
          <head>His Place Is the Home.</head>
          <p>A woman in California is said to be circulating a petition for the recall of her husband from public office.</p>
		  <p>She feels, perhaps, that she does not want the father of her children contaminated by politics. C.B.</p>
        </div>
        <div type="section" n="">
          <head>One Reason Why.</head>
          <p>Speaking of the difficulties of women doctors, and the lack of regulations and licenses for midwives in this country, we recall an editorial in the "Boston Medical and Surgical Journal," which said: "The serious inroads made by female physicians in obstetrical business, one of the essential branches of income to a majority of well established practitioners" . . . . </p>
        </div>
        </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>