<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="https://tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="https://cwrc.ca/templates/css/tei.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
	<teiHeader>
		 <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
				<title>Are Women People?</title>
				<author>Alice Duer Miller</author>
				<editor>Amelia Flynn</editor>
				<respStmt>
					<resp>TEI Encoding</resp>
					<name>Amelia Flynn</name>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>CTS*4020: Digital Research Project</publisher>
				<address>
					<orgName>University of Guelph</orgName>
					<settlement>Guelph</settlement>
					<postCode>N1G 2W1</postCode>
					<country>Canada</country>
				</address>
				<date when="2025">2025</date>
				<distributor>University of Guelph</distributor>
				<authority>Amelia Flynn</authority>
			</publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl>
          <title>Are Women People?</title>
          <title>New York Tribune</title>
          <note>Column</note>
          <date>1915-02-07</date>
        </bibl>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
		<xenoData><rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:as="http://www.w3.org/ns/activitystreams#" xmlns:cwrc="http://sparql.cwrc.ca/ontologies/cwrc#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:geo="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#" xmlns:oa="http://www.w3.org/ns/oa#" xmlns:schema="http://schema.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#" xmlns:fabio="https://purl.org/spar/fabio#" xmlns:bf="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/bif#" xmlns:cito="https://sparontologies.github.io/cito/current/cito.html#" xmlns:org="http://www.w3.org/ns/org#"/></xenoData></teiHeader>
<text>
    <front>
      <div type="header">
		<dateline>February 7, 1915</dateline>
        <head type="main">ARE WOMEN PEOPLE?</head>
        <head type="sub">By Alice Duer Miller</head>
      </div>
    </front>

    <body>
      <div type="article">
        <div type="section" n="">
          <head>TO SUSAN B. ANTHONY.
          </head>
          <p/>
          <lg>
            <l>SOMETHING there was that you imagined not,</l>
            <l>For all your wisdom, temperate and high,</l>
            <l>How unto us, to whom the kinder years</l>
            <l>Secure a fairer fight, an easier lot,</l>
            <l>Your name would be a creed, a battle cry,</l>
            <l>A silver trumpet blowing to the sky,</l>
            <l>Steeling our hearts, filling our eyes with tears,</l>
            <l>Giving us fire and fortitude and love;</l>
            <l>This was, alas! a thing you never guessed—</l>
            <l>How younger women whom you knew not of</l>
            <l>Would rise and call you blessed.</l>
            
          </lg>
          
        </div>
        <div type="section" n="">
          <head>PROPERTY RIGHTS.
            
          </head>
          <p>The other day in New York a man, suffering from financial reverses, killed his wife and two grown daughters, but spared his son.
          </p>
          <p>"In the assumption," says one of the papers, "that he believed Lester could get along because he was a boy, lies the only reasonable explanation of the fact that <persName>Auerbach</persName> spared his son's life."
          </p>
          <p>The two girls were wage earners. The boy was only fourteen and still in school.
          </p>
          <p>This assumption is not reasonable.
          </p>
          <p>Auerbach spared his son's life because he did not feel that he had the right to take it. With the women of his family he did feel he had this right.
          </p>
          
        </div>
        <div type="section" n="">
          <head>A NEW VIEW OF THE FEMALE SEX.
            
          </head>
          <p><persName>Mr. Kipling</persName>, according to "The Times," writing in a letter to a French friend, speaks of the psychology of the Germans.
          </p>
          <p>"I am stupified," he says."I never could have imagined a nation in a frenzy. It is a race of women. . . . The Germans have only the sabre in their philosophy. As you say, it is the problem of the mad dog."
          </p>
          <p>Only the italics are our own, but they seem to us the best thing in the paragraph.
          </p>
          <p/>
          <p/>
        </div>
        <div type="section" n="">
          <head>SOMETHING HARDER NEXT TIME.
            
          </head>
          <p>"How comes it," demands the woman's protest, "that the suffragists nearly all come from non-suffrage states?"
          </p>
          <p>For the same reason that there are no votes-for-men leagues in all this broad democracy.
          </p>
        </div>
        <div type="section" n="">
          <head>A MILD BOAST.
            
          </head>
          <p>We learn from the same paper that the various state associations opposed to woman suffrage have sent $6,000 to sufferers in Europe.
          </p>
          <p>As the anti's claim to represent 90 per cent of American womanhood, and as there are about 25,000,000 women in this country, these figures show; if our arithmetic is not mistaken, that each anti contributed three one-hundredths of one cent to war relief.
          </p>
          <p>In seeking names of women after whom to name the public schools of New York, a correspondent suggests the following list, as representing those who have done most for the best interests of their sex: 
          </p>
          <p><persName>Miss Lurelina Petty</persName>, who drowned rather than learn to swim—an exercise which she considered unfeminine.
          </p>
          <p><persName>Mrs. Rosalind House</persName>, who, in the absence of her husband, starved to death, rather than leave her home for any reason whatsoever.
          </p>
          <p><persName>Miss Caraminitta T. Grace</persName>, who refused ever to learn to read or write, lest she should be distracted from her domestic duties.
          </p>
          <p><persName>Miss Lily Mabel Sweet</persName>, who committed suicide on learning that she would have to contaminate herself in the mire of politics in order to get a marriage license from the City Hall.
          </p>
          
        </div>
        <div type="section" n="">
          <head>PLEASING TO THOSE WHO LIKE THAT SORT OF THING.
            
          </head>
          <p>Well it seems we were all wrong in objecting to the remarks of <persName>Mr. Bowdle</persName>, of Ohio, on the subject of women—their feet, their ankles, the hooking and unhooking of their dresses, the rallying of wives round the pay check, and the fact that all history is nothing but the record of an affair with a woman.
          </p>
          <p>The president of the Connecticut Association Opposed to Woman Suffrage enjoyed every word of it.
          </p>
          <p>"Mr. Bowdle, of Ohio," she writes, "one of the strongest and most effective speakers, used that most telling weapon, ridicule, and in so doing carried with resistless force the Speaker, the house and the galleries— except the suffrage contingent."
          </p>
        </div>
        <div type="section" n="">
          <head>
          </head>
          <p>(“Where on earth did this idea come from that the ballot is a boon, a privilege and an honor? From men.”—<persName>Mrs. Prestonia Mann Martin</persName>.)
          </p>
          <lg>
            <lg><l>Who is it thinks the vote some use?</l>
            <l>Man. (Man is often such a goose!)</l>
            <l>Indeed, it makes me laugh to see</l>
            <l>How men have struggled to be free.</l></lg>
            
            <lg><l>Poor <persName>Washington</persName>, who meant so well,</l>
            <l>And <persName>Nathan Hale</persName> and <persName>William Tell</persName>,</l>
            <l><persName>Hampden</persName> and <persName>Bolivar</persName> and <persName>Pym</persName>,</l>
            <l>And <persName>L'Ouverture</persName>—remember him?</l></lg>
            
            <lg><l>And <persName>Garibaldi</persName> and <persName>Kossuth</persName>,</l>
            <l>And some who threw away their youth,</l>
            <l>All bitten by the stupid notion</l>
            <l>That liberty was worth emotion.</l></lg>
            
            <lg><l>They could not get it through their heads</l>
            <l>That if they stayed tucked up in beds,</l>
            <l>Avoiding politics and strife,</l>
            <l>They'd lead a pleasant, peaceful life.</l></lg>
            
            <lg><l>Let us, dear sisters, never make</l>
            <l>Such a ridiculous mistake;</l>
            <l>But teach our children o'er and o'er</l>
            <l>That liberty is just a chore.</l></lg>
            
          </lg>
        </div>
        </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>